Guide to the Ralph Hodgson Papers
Yale University Library
- Correspondence, 1887-1976; Series I.; 16.2' (40 boxes)
  - PERMISSIONS
    - Chisholm, Louey, 1928 Feb 6 (Box 31, Folder 643)
    - Colgan, Molly, 1956-57 (Box 31, Folder 644)
    - "D-F" general, 1948-58 (Box 31, Folder 645)
    - English Association, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 646)
    - Finlayson, Allan S., Jr., 1938 (Box 31, Folder 647)
    - Fleet Publications, 1946 (Box 31, Folder 648)
    - Fogerty, Elsie, 1920-29 (Box 31, Folder 649)
    - Fougasse
      See: Bird, Kenneth, Box 31 folder 637
    - "G" general, 1931-69 (Box 31, Folder 650)
    - Ginn Company Ltd., 1960 (Box 31, Folder 651)
    - "H" general, 1927, 1940 (Box 31, Folder 652)
    - Harris, Addena, [1961]-62 (Box 31, Folder 653)
    - Hoffman, Edwin M., 1944-[54] (Box 31, Folder 654)
      See also: Oversize, box 65, folder 1143
    - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1936-38 (Box 31, Folder 655)
    - Hutchings, Monica, 1947 Oct 30 (Box 31, Folder 656)
    - "K" general, 1914, 1954 (Box 31, Folder 657)
    - Kettering and District Eisteddfod, 1948-49 (Box 31, Folder 658)
    - "L" general, 1932-57 (Box 31, Folder 659)
    - Longmans, Green Co. Limited, 1924-58 (Box 31, Folder 660)
    - "M" general, 1935-42 (Box 31, Folder 661)
    - Macmillan Company, 1918-72 (Box 31, Folder 662-663)
    - Marie Louise, Princess, 1922-24 (Box 31, Folder 664)
    - Markham, Edwin, 1926 Oct (Box 31, Folder 665)
    - Minerva Publishing House, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 666)
    - "N" general, 1940-49, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 667)
    - National Library for the Blind, 1949-61 (Box 32, Folder 668)
    - O'Driscoll, Loretta, 1972-73 (Box 32, Folder 669)
    - Oxford University Press, 1935, 1946 (Box 32, Folder 670)
    - "P" general, 1926-46 (Box 32, Folder 671)
    - People's Dispensary for Sick Animals, 1949 (Box 32, Folder 672)
    - Poetry Magazine, 1916-31, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 673)
    - "R" general, 1921-42, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 674)
    - "S" general, 1923-46 (Box 32, Folder 675)
    - Sato, Yoshibumi, 1956-58 (Box 32, Folder 676)
    - Simon and Schuster, 1942-52 (Box 32, Folder 677)
    - Spies, Claudio, 1949-50 (Box 32, Folder 678)
      See also: Oversize, box 65, folder 1144
    - Stevens, Ethel Williams, 1926-37 (Box 32, Folder 679)
      See: Oversize, box 65, folder 1145
    - Stratford-upon-Avon Festival of Britain Committee, 1951 (Box 32, Folder 680)
    - Swarup, Brahma, [1956]-71 (Box 32, Folder 681)
    - "T" general, 1942-72 (Box 32, Folder 682)
    - Teasdale, Sara, 1921 Oct 28 (Box 32, Folder 683)
    - Topliffe, Carleton Veda, 1946-47 (Box 32, Folder 684)
    - The University of Chicago, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 685)
    - University of Minnesota, 1932 Aug 1 (Box 32, Folder 686)
    - The Viking Press, Inc., 1941 May 8 (Box 32, Folder 687)
    - "W" general, 1919-54 (Box 32, Folder 688)
    - Walters, L. D'O., 1914 Nov 7 (Box 32, Folder 689)
    - Watts, Harry, 1932-[35?] (Box 32, Folder 690)
    - Wellesley, Dorothy, 1939 Apr 16 (Box 32, Folder 691)
    - Wellesley, Kenneth, 1958-60 (Box 32, Folder 692)
    - Wollman, Maurice, 1936-46 (Box 32, Folder 693)
    - Yeats, W. B., [1935 Oct.]
      See: Oxford University Press, Box 32 folder 670
  - PUBLISHERS INQUIRIES
    - "A-C" general, 1921-60 (Box 32, Folder 694)
    - A. C. Black Ltd., [1935-57] (Box 32, Folder 695-697)
    - Adams, Elbridge L.
      See: The Fountain Press, Box 33 folder 710
    - Alfred A. Knopf Publisher, 1916-48 (Box 32, Folder 698)
    - Asquith, Cynthia, 1927 Oct 20 (Box 32, Folder 699)
    - Ballantine Books, Inc., 1952 (Box 32, Folder 700)
    - Carlyle Straub Publisher, 1936-38 (Box 32, Folder 701)
    - The Cayme Press Limited, 1928 Oct 6 (Box 32, Folder 702)
    - Church, Richard
      See: J.M. Dent in "I-L" general, Box 33 folder 713
    - Christopher Publishing House, 1942-45 (Box 33, Folder 703)
    - "D-E" general, 1935-49 (Box 33, Folder 704)
    - Doubleday Company, Inc., 1940-48 (Box 33, Folder 705)
    - Everybody's, 1949-53 (Box 33, Folder 706-707)
    - "F-G" general, 1935-49, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 708)
    - Florida Magazine of Verse, 1942 (Box 33, Folder 709)
    - The Fountain Press, 1929 Oct 31 (Box 33, Folder 710)
    - H.W. Wilson Company, 1939 (Box 33, Folder 711)
    - Harper Brothers, 1946 Nov 29 (Box 33, Folder 712)
    - "I-L" general, 1922-62 (Box 33, Folder 713)
    - Institute for Research in Biography, 1944-52 (Box 33, Folder 714)
    - The London Mercury, 1919-22 (Box 33, Folder 715)
    - "M-R" general, 1915-[70] (Box 33, Folder 716)
    - March Monthly, 1959-60 (Box 33, Folder 717)
    - Reed, Edward Bliss
      See: The Yale Review, Box 33 folder 725
    - Richards, Grant
      See: The Cayme Press Limited, Box 32 folder 702
    - "S" general, 1927-55 (Box 33, Folder 718)
    - Shanks, Edward, 1919-46 (Box 33, Folder 719)
    - Squire, John Collings, Sir
      See: The London Mercury, Box 33 folder 715
    - "T-Y" general, 1938-62 (Box 33, Folder 720)
    - Tillotson, Geoffrey, 1950 (Box 33, Folder 721)
    - University of Kansas City Review, 1949-57 (Box 33, Folder 722-724)
      See also: Oversize, box 67, folder 1189
    - The Yale Review, 1916 Apr 5 (Box 33, Folder 725)
    - Yale University Press, 1916 Nov 29 (Box 33, Folder 726)
  - ORDERS
    - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 33, Folder 727-728)
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 33, Folder 729-732)
    - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 33, Folder 733)
    - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 34, Folder 734)
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 34, Folder 735)
    - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 34, Folder 736-737)
    - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 34, Folder 738)
    - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 34, Folder 739)
    - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 34, Folder 740)
    - Correspondence, 1950-52 (Box 34, Folder 741)
    - Correspondence, 1953-55 (Box 34, Folder 742)
    - Correspondence, 1956-57 (Box 34, Folder 743)
    - Correspondence, 1958-59 (Box 34, Folder 744)
    - Correspondence, 1960-74 (Box 34, Folder 745)
    - Correspondence (Box 34, Folder 746)
  - OTHER REQUESTS AND INVITATIONS
    - "A" general, 1938-60 (Box 34, Folder 747)
    - "B" general, 1923-56 (Box 34, Folder 748)
    - Bread Loaf Writers' Conference, 1939 May 16 (Box 34, Folder 749)
    - British Vice Consulate, Cleveland, Ohio, 1942 Sep 22 (Box 34, Folder 750)
    - "C" general, 1936-59 (Box 34, Folder 751)
    - The Canton Repository, 1950 (Box 35, Folder 752)
    - Central School of Speech Training and Dramatic Art
      See: Fogerty, Elsie in Permissions, Box 31 folder 649
    - Eckhauser, Irwin, 1964 Apr 1 (Box 35, Folder 753)
    - Elliott Fry Ltd., 1936-39 (Box 35, Folder 754)
    - "F-G" general, 1922-62 (Box 35, Folder 755)
    - Golding, Louis, 1919 Jan 29 (Box 35, Folder 756)
    - "H" general, 1934-37 (Box 35, Folder 757)
    - Hargail Music Press, 1947 (Box 35, Folder 758)
    - Harvard Law School Record, 1946-47 (Box 35, Folder 759)
    - Hockey, Lawrence W., 1946, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 760)
    - Kershner, A. G., Jr., 1950-51 (Box 35, Folder 761)
    - Kuhn, Marie, 1946 (Box 35, Folder 762)
    - "L" general, 1921-39 (Box 35, Folder 763)
    - Library of Congress, 1939-59 (Box 35, Folder 764)
    - "M" general, 1923-66 (Box 35, Folder 765)
    - Miller, Paul W., 1972 (Box 35, Folder 766)
    - Morrison, Theodore
      See: Bread Loaf Writers' Conference, Box 34 folder 749
    - Mount Union College, 1946-68, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 767)
    - "N-O" general, 1939-60 (Box 35, Folder 768)
    - Ohio Poetry Day, 1944-59 (Box 35, Folder 769)
    - "P-R" general, 1928-[60] (Box 35, Folder 770)
    - "S" general, 1921-63 (Box 35, Folder 771)
    - Salomon, I. L., 1950 (Box 35, Folder 772)
    - Stonesifer, Richard J., 1951-52 (Box 35, Folder 773)
    - "U" general, 1939, 1962 (Box 35, Folder 774)
    - University of Buffalo, 1936-37 (Box 35, Folder 775)
    - University of Louisville, 1966 (Box 35, Folder 776)
    - Ursinus College, [1948-49] (Box 35, Folder 777)
    - Watson, R. L., 1942-47 (Box 35, Folder 778)
    - Weeks, A. L., 1955-60, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 779)
    - Whitehead, Victor F., 1917 Oct 26 (Box 36, Folder 780)
    - Winsten, Stephen, 1950-53 (Box 36, Folder 781-782)
  - FAN MAIL
    - Correspondence, 1917-19 (Box 36, Folder 783)
    - Correspondence, 1922-29 (Box 36, Folder 784)
      See also: Oversize, box 64, folder 1133
    - Correspondence, 1930 (Box 36, Folder 785)
    - Correspondence, 1931-32 (Box 36, Folder 786)
    - Correspondence, 1933 (Box 36, Folder 787)
    - Correspondence, 1934 (Box 36, Folder 788)
    - Correspondence, 1935-36 (Box 36, Folder 789)
    - Correspondence, 1937-39 (Box 36, Folder 790)
    - Correspondence, 1941-42 (Box 36, Folder 791)
    - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 36, Folder 792)
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 36, Folder 793)
    - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 36, Folder 794-797)
    - Correspondence, 1947-48 (Box 36, Folder 798)
    - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 36, Folder 799)
    - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 36, Folder 800)
    - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 37, Folder 801)
    - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 37, Folder 802)
    - Correspondence, 1953-54 (Box 37, Folder 803)
    - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 37, Folder 804)
    - Correspondence, 1956-58 (Box 37, Folder 805)
    - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 37, Folder 806-812)
    - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 813-814)
    - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 38, Folder 815-819)
    - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 820-825)
    - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 38, Folder 826)
    - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 827)
    - Correspondence, 1965-76 (Box 38, Folder 828)
    - Correspondence (Box 38, Folder 829)
  - RELATED MATERIAL
    - Notes by Aurelia Hodgson about the correspondence (Box 39, Folder 829a-829c)
      With draft of letter to Bryher at front of one notebook
    - Miscellaneous addresses, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 830)
    - Blank stationery, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 831)
    - Empty envelopes, 1922-72, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 832)
- Writings, 1810-1971; Series II.; 1.0' (3 boxes)
  Series II, Writings, is organized into two subseries: Writings by Ralph Hodgson, and Writings by Others. Writings by Ralph Hodgson is arranged alphabetically by title, and Writings by Others is arranged alphabetically by author.
  - WRITINGS BY RALPH HODGSON
    - "The Boxers 1913" The Saturday Review 115 (June 7 1913) photocopy, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 833)
    - "The Bull-Terrier: The Policeman of the Hearth" Fry's Magazine 12 (Feb. 1910) photocopy, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 834)
    - "England's Disappearing Dogs" Fry's Magazine 1 (Apr. 1911) photocopy (Box 40, Folder 835)
    - "A Flying Scroll, No. 4 and 5" galley proofs, 1945
      See: Oversize, box 67, folder 1189
    - "Memories of Poets, 1910-1920" typescript draft, corrected, and later typescript, corrected, [1943] (Box 40, Folder 836)
      Text of a lecture given by Hodgson in Ypsilanti, Michigan in 1943
    - "More Poems by Ralph Hodgson" page proof, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 837)
    - "A Poem by Ralph Hodgson" page proof, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 838)
    - "Old Books" typescript draft, corrected, with two later typescripts, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 839)
    - "On Buying a Puppy" Fry's Magazine 14 (Jan. 1911) photocopy, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 840)
    - "Silver Wedding and Other Poems" pamphlet
      See: Box 26, folder 523
    - "Some Popular Fallacies Concerning Dogs" Fry's Magazine 14 (Feb. 1911) photocopy, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 841)
    - "Songs to Our Surnames" pamphlet, n.d.
      See: Box 26, folder 525
    - Without Comment, ed. by Hodgson, typescript, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 842-846)
    - Copyright certificates for Flying Scrolls and Silver Wedding and Other Poems, 1941-48 (Box 40, Folder 846a)
    - Two pages of a part of a poem[?], holograph, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 847)
    - Fragments of one poem[?], holograph and typescript (Box 40, Folder 848)
  - WRITINGS BY OTHERS
    - Arkenburgh, Miriam Vedder. "Small Hour in Smyrna" holograph poem, 1961
      See: Box 1, folder 14
    - B., Alex. B. "I am the heir of the ages ..." autograph manuscript poem in unidentified hand, 1914 Jun (Box 40, Folder 849)
    - Bagnold, Enid
      - "Epitaph on W......" typescript poem, 1918
        See: Box 2, folder 25
      - "Lines, on Suddenly Waking" typescript poem, 1916
      - "To clean your shag-filled briar..." typescript poem, 1922
    - Beyer, William. "Hermit" typescript poem, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 850)
    - Blunden, Edmund
      - "Almswomen" holograph poem, 1921 Apr 2 (Box 40, Folder 851)
      - "A First Impression" holograph poem, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 852)
      - The Muse of Munster or The Hedge- Schoolmaster's Helicon Hibernian Harmonist notebook of holograph poems, 1925 (Box 40, Folder 853)
      - "My Funny Old Dress" holograph poem, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 854)
      - "The Sale" holograph poem, 1921 [Dec] (Box 40, Folder 855)
      - Sundries small booklet of holograph poems, with drawing on last page (Box 40, Folder 856)
      - "Very Jewels in their Fair Estate" holograph poem, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 857)
      - Verses by John Clare: "Broken memory of the Sonnet referred to at p. 127" and "Clare's Last Verses [p. 128]" holograph poems (Box 40, Folder 857a)
        Removed from John Clare, Life and Remains of John Clare, the "Northamptonshire Peasant Poet." London: Frederick Warne Co, 1873
    - Bracy, Carla. Eight poems, typescripts, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 858)
    - Bynner, Witter. "O For a Witless Age" typescript poem, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 859)
    - Cartwright, H. Arthur. Three poems, typescripts, 1960 (Box 40, Folder 860)
    - Cruttwell, Elizabeth
      - "Hampton Court" typescript poems, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 861)
      - "Holt's Hens" typescript poems, inscribed, 1958 May (Box 40, Folder 862)
      - "The Just Proportion" typescript poems, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 863)
      - "Lyrics from Hampton Court" typescript photocopy, signed, 1959 Sep 11 (Box 40, Folder 864)
    - Dalmon, Charles
      - "The Jolly Tinker" holograph poem, [1932]
        See: Box 7, folder 126
      - "Odds and Ends by Charles Dalmon" 14 holograph poems
    - Denson, Alan
      - "Invocation" typescript poem, 1960
        See: Box 7, folder 144
      - "Lullaby" holograph poem, 1953
        See: Box 7, folder 143
      - "Stellar Music" holograph poem, 1953
      - "Storming Song" holograph poem, 1953
      - Two holograph poems, 1952
    - Doi, Kochi
      - Interview with Edmund Blunden, typescript
        See: Box 7, folder 146
      - "Ralph Hodgson," typescript photocopy, n.d.
        See: Box 20, folder 401
      - Recollection of Ralph Hodgson, typescript, corrected, n.d.
    - Drinkwater, John. "A Slum Piece" holograph poem inscribed to Hodgson, typescript of same poem, signed by Drinkwater, n.d.
      See: Box 8, folder 151
    - Eigo Bungaku Sekai vol. 6, no. 6. Ralph Hodgson issue. Translated by Takahiro Kamogawa. Typescript, corrected, 1971 Sep
      See: Box 20, folder 405
    - Eliot, T. S.
      - "Lines to Ralph Hodgson Esqre." and "[How Unpleasant to Know Mr. Eliot!]" typescript poems with pen and ink sketches at top of each, [1932 Aug 16]
        See: Box 9, folder 167
      - "Old Possum's Book of Practical Cats with pixtures [sic] supplied by The Man in White Spats" typescript carbon, corrected by Eliot (Box 40, Folder 865)
    - Fujii, Haruhiko. "On 'Tributes to Ralph Hodgson'" typescript, [1972]
      See: Box 10, folder 202
    - Gaige, Crosby. Three holograph poems, signed by author and inscribed to Hodgson, 1928 May (Box 40, Folder 866)
      Poems are entitled: "Verse Written with James Stephens' Pen," "To J. S.", and "Little Bird, Little Wren"
    - Goldman, Peretz. Thirty holograph poems, [1847 Oct] (Box 40, Folder 866a)
    - Hillyer, Robert. "Elizabethan Pastoral Landscape" typescript, corrected
      See: Box 12, folder 246
    - Hodgson, Aurelia, ed. Tributes to Ralph Hodgson on a Hundredth Birthday September 9, 1971
      - Clipping of "On Reading 'Song of Honour' by Ralph Hodgson" by Carolus, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 867)
      - Photocopy of "To a Dead Drunk" by James Wright, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 868)
      - Typescript and carbon typescript (Box 41, Folder 869)
      - Galley proofs, corrected, n.d.
        See: Oversize, box 65, folder 1146
      - Printed by the Boerner Printing Co., Minerva, Ohio, 1971 (Box 41, Folder 870)
    - Hutchinson, Sherry. Five poems, typescript, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 871)
    - Ishii, Naonobu. Four typescript poems, corrected, signed by author, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 872)
      One untitled, the other three entitled: "Mizzle in Autumn," "The World is a Haunted-Ship," "Seeking a Lee"
    - Kinney, Richard. "Heart of the Mystery," typescript poem, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 872a)
    - Kirkconnell, Watson. "Ta Grammata" printed poem, corrected, inscribed to Hodgson, [1932] (Box 41, Folder 873)
    - Kirkup, James. "Sons of the North," typescript, corrected, [1971]
      See: Box 14, folder 280
    - Kobayashi, Atsuo. "A Chauffeur's Story," holograph, n.d.
      See: Box 27, folder 549
    - Maas, William
      - "The Birds of Barleyvale," typescript, corrected, n.d.
        See: Box 15, folder 310
      - "Blunt Theory and Sharp Practice," typescript carbon, corrected
        See: Box 15, folder 312
      - "Calling All Dogs," typescript carbon, n.d.
        See: Box 15, folder 313
      - "Flowers in Revolt," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d.
        See: Box 15, folder 307
      - "An Idyl of Hillside Warren," typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - "A Servant of Destiny," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d.
        See: Box 15, folder 308
      - "Trouble Makers," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d.
    - McKenna, Michael. Privately issued memorial volume for McKenna, edited by Hodgson. Galleys, corrected by Hodgson, incomplete, n.d.
      See: Oversize, box 68a, folder 1192
    - Magnus, Barbara J. "Ralph Hodgson, Muse-ician" typescript, corrected, [1933] (Box 41, Folder 874)
    - Meynell, Everard. Four poems, holograph, corrected, n.d.
      See: Box 17, folder 339
    - Mickle, William Julius. "There's Nae Luck About the House" holograph poem with title page, in Edmund Blunden's hand? (Box 41, Folder 875)
    - Moncrieff, George Scott."In Spring" typescript poem, n.d.
      See: Box 17, folder 343
    - Moriya, Yone. "[I toiled...]" typescript poem, signed, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 876)
    - Morley, Christopher. "Clinical Notes by a Resident Patient" in The Baker Street Journal Vol. 1, No. 4, 1946 (Box 41, Folder 876a)
      Article quotes a letter from Hodgson to Morley
    - Oakley, Ruth
      - Fourteen poems inscribed to Hodgson, typescript, corrected, [1960]
        See: Box 19, folder 381
      - Resurgum. 51 Poems, 1945-51. King George VI, 1952, typescript, corrected, 1961
        See: Box 19, folder 382
      - Three poems, typescript, 1959
        See: Box 19, folder 380
    - O'Hara, Kyoko. "On Master Ralph Hodgson, Again!" typescript essay, n.d.
      See: Box 19, folder 396
    - Pancoast, Sherry
    - Paul, Laura Rankin. Fifty-four poems, holograph and typescript, 1946-49 (Box 41, Folder 877)
    - Poems gathered by Norman Holmes Pearson for Hodgson's 90th birthday, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 878)
    - Richards, Robert F. "Ralph Hodgson, Poet and Person" typescript
      See: Box 22, folder 432
    - [Rothenstein, William?] Ten holograph poems, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 879)
    - Sakabe, Shigeyoshi. "Ralph Hodgson" typescript inscribed to Hodgson, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 880)
    - Smith, LeRoy, Jr.
      - "The Fourth King" typescript, signed, 1952
        See: Box 27, folder 530
      - "Punishment Enough," typescript poem, 1949 Apr
        See: Box 27, folder 529
    - Stein, Gertrude. "Cultivated Motor Automatism: A Study of Character in its Relation to Attention" typed transcript of article in the Psychological Review, 1898, pp. 295-306, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 881)
    - Stephens, James.
      - "At eve the horse is freed of plough ..." holograph poem, 1914
        See: Box 27, folder 540
      - "Irony," typescript poem, n.d.
      - "The lovely moon trailing her silver dress..." holograph poem, 1914
    - Stires, David. Four poems, typescripts, signed, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 882)
      Entitled: "The Malvern Hills," "Twilight," "In Your Sleep," "To My Love"
    - Taketomo, Tarao. "To Ralph Hodgson," holograph poem, n.d.
      See: Box 28, folder 556
    - Turner, W. J. Smaragda's Lover. A Dramatic Phantasmagoria London: Chatto Windus. Proof, corrected, 1924 (Box 42, Folder 883)
    - Whistler, Laurence. Nine poems, typescript, corrected. With two sheets of notes on the poems in Hodgson's hand, 1951 Nov (Box 42, Folder 884)
    - Wintle, Mrs. Miscellanies. Verse Bound volume of holograph poems, 1810 (Box 42, Folder 885)
    - Young, Douglas. "Reflections at Stand-to," typescript
      See: Box 30, folder 615
    - Unidentified. "Adonais XII" holograph poem, corrected, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 886)
    - Unidentified. Bound volume with autograph poem "To Kingston Fleet Esqr.", ca. 1830? (Box 42, Folder 887)
      Inscribed on front flyleaf "Agnes Klipsch, Evesham, 1837"
- Artwork, 1796-1951; Series III.; 1.0' (3 boxes)
  Series III, Artwork is organized into two subseries: Artwork by Hodgson, and Artwork by Others. Artwork by Hodgson is arranged alphabetically by title or supplied descriptive title, and Artwork by Others is arranged by artist. Artwork by unidentified artists has been placed at the end of Artwork by Others.
  - ARTWORK BY HODGSON
    - Ainu chief and his son, drawing in pencil, [betw. 1927 1934]
      See: Oversize, box 65, folder 1147
    - Birds sitting on their eggs, three sketches, inscribed to Aurelia Hodgson, 1933 Apr 20 (Box 43, Folder 888)
    - "The Black Redstart?" drawing in pen and ink and colored pencil, [1933] (Box 43, Folder 888a)
    - Booklouse, drawing in pencil, with one page of holograph notes, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 889)
    - Cartoons and sketches of people, twenty in pencil and pen and ink
      See: Oversize, box 65, folder 1148
    - Cartoons, fifty-nine in pen and ink and crayon, set in the 1920s and 1930s, [1937 Feb]
      See: Oversize, box 66, folders 1168-1188
      Color reproduction of "Bookhunting Old Style" below (folder 891)
    - "Chuffy," four sketches of Hodgson's dog, in pencil, with four sketches of unidentified dogs, in pencil, 1949-50, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 890)
    - "Henry Salt," seven color plates of a Hodgson drawing (Box 43, Folder 891)
      Original titled "Bookhunting Old Style" in the collection of fifty- nine cartoons (see box 66, folder 1186)
    - "Jenny" three sketches of a yellow bird, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 892)
    - Landscapes, four rough sketches in pencil, 1932-50, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 893)
      Two untitled, two titled: "Autumn," and "Pantelaria"
    - "Love Me, Love My Dog" two printed broadsides, n.d.
      See: Oversize, bsd, folder 1211
      Drawings of famous authors and their recorded remarks about dogs
    - "Osprey" sketch with notes, in pencil and crayon, 1950 Sep 7 (Box 43, Folder 894)
    - "Patch" sketchbook containing two sketches, in pencil, 1939-42 (Box 43, Folder 895)
      Patch was Hodgson's bull terrier. Accompanied by another sketch in pencil of Patch and notes from a dream about the dog after its death
    - Six miscellaneous sketches of people and a tree, in pen and ink and crayon, and in pencil and watercolor, 1949-50, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 896)
    - Sketchbook, "Dickens etc. Cardboard cut out characters" pencil drawings and paper cut outs (Box 43, Folder 897-898)
      With a folder of drawings laid into sketchbook loosely
    - Sketchbook of soldiers at Lowestoft, England, pen and ink and watercolor, [1914-15?] (Box 43, Folder 899)
      Sketches of seventeen men, officers in the Royal Navy, at Lowestoft, where Hodgson served in World War I
    - "Sleepy Meg" and two other sketches of girls sleeping, two in pencil, and one in pen and ink, 1939-40, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 900)
    - Three small sketches in pen and ink of a man and a dog, and a sailing ship (Box 43, Folder 901)